Md. Shirajul Islam

Independent Development Consultant

Professional Software Engineer on .NET

shirajul.mamun@gmail.com

Contact: +8801710318199



Summary

- 8+ years of experience on consulting on .NET based solution.
- 9+ years of experience on software development.
- 9+ years of experience on Providing Training on .NET Technologies.

Very passionate about software development and related fields. I am interested to learn in depth knowledge in topics rather than floating on and jumping around.

Worked as a Software Engineer, Team Lead, Development Lead and Consultant in various period of time on IT Industry. Professional speaker about .NET technologies. I consider myself as a life-long learner, sharing the knowledge with industry peer is part of my learning, cause sharing makes me more understanding on topics.

I love to learn with team, work with team, it's nice to collaborate with human.

Experience

Founder, CEO

Enlight Solutions

Independent Development Consultant on .NET

September 2017 - Present

Lead Trainer on Professional ASP.NET MVC at BASIS Institute of Technology & Management (BITM) (Part-Time)

September 2016 - Present

- * Conduct Training on Professional ASP.NET MVC
- * Provide Mentorship on Project work

Development Lead, Senior Software Engineer at Nerd Castle Limited

February 2016 - April 2017 (1 year 3 months)

- Ensure the architectural alignment of written code by team member.
- Understanding requirements and adopt changes according to client's expectation.
- Provide technical leadership, training and constant mentorship to team members.
- Breakdown requirement to user stories.

• Solve critical issues on any phase on development cycle.

Trainer at BASIS Institute of Technology & Management (BITM)

March 2014 - September 2016

Provide training to freshers/professional on Object Oriented Programming and on .NET based technologies

Development Consultant at Nerd Castle Limited

May 2017 - August 2017 (4 months)

Senior Software Engineer Team Lead & Senior Trainer/Consultant at Nerd Castle Limited

February 2015 - February 2016 (1 year 1 month)

- Ensure the architectural alignment of written code by team member.
- Understanding requirements and adopt changes according to client's expectation.
- Provide technical leadership, training and constant mentorship to team members.
- Breakdown requirement to user stories.
- Solve critical issues on any phase on development cycle.
- Provide training to several training programs
- Review and repair legacy code

Consultant for Programming in Professional C# Language at Bording Vista Ltd. (part-time)

September 2015 - September 2015 (1 month)

It was a 5 day long training which was conducted for new recruited six employees of Boarding Vista on professional programming in C#.

Achievement:

The all 6 employees got certified on Programming in C# (70-483) after attending the training.

Software Engineer at BRAC IT Services Limited

May 2014 - January 2015 (9 months)

Development Software on various banking related solution..

- Physical Document archiving System
- Analysis on the user requirement, design the architecture of the solution, develop the system as per user requirement.
- Bulk Pay Order Printing Tool
- Pay Order Printing tool for Brac Bank
- Customer Complaint management system for Brac Bank
- Involved in existing system development on customer complaint management system internally know as ITracker.

Software Engineer at Periscope Technology Solutions Limited

November 2012 - April 2014 (1 year 6 months)

- ERP Solution Development
- Warehouse Module
- Core Financial Module
- Core Inventory Module
- Core Sales Module
- Research on Month End Processing
- Design Balancesheet Report and other financial reports in SSRS etc...

Junior Software Engineer at Nerd Castle

November 2011 - October 2012 (1 year)

Nerd Castle

- Core development of Software according to design
- Refactoring existing code.
- Unit Testing

Education

Sammilani Institute

CGPA: 4.75 out of 5

Secondary School Certification, Science, 2002 - 2003

Jessore Cantonment College

CGPA: 4.6 out of 5

H.S.C, Science, 2004 - 2005

Islamic University, Kushtia

CGPA 3.17 out of 4

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Computer Science and Engineering, 2006 – 2010

Activities and Societies: Islamic University Computer Association

Personal Information

Father's Name: Ismail Hossain Mother's Name: Afzalunnesa.

Religion : Islam. **Gender :** Male.

Date of Birth: 15th August 1989 **Nationality:** Bangladeshi.

Maritial Status: Single

National ID No.: 4114741262564